<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2019 Kevin Degeling -->

<component type="desktop">
  <id>com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum</id>
  <name>Q-Zandronum</name>
  <summary>A Zandronum 3.0 fork with improved netcode, configurable movement and many small tweaks</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Sleepycat</project_license>

  <developer_name>Q-Zandronum &amp; Doomseeker team</developer_name>
  <update_contact>kreato@kreato.dev</update_contact>

  <url type="homepage">https://qzandronum.com/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/IgeNiaI/Q-Zandronum/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://discord.gg/u4ptaMk</url>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum.desktop</launchable>

  <description>
    <p>
	    Q-Zandronum is a fork of Zandronum, a multiplayer oriented port, based off Skulltag, for Doom and Doom II by id Software.
	    The main goal of the fork is to improve the QC:DE gameplay, but it can be used with other mods as well. The engine brings improved netcode, multiple Quality-of-Life improvements and new modding features.
    </p>
    <p>
      In some scenarios, commercial data files are required to run the supported games. In other cases, it's possibly to automatically use Freedoom as a drop-in replacement. This package comes bundled with Doomseeker for easy installation and server browsing.
    </p>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum/master/images/image_01.png</image>
      <caption>Doom multiplayer</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum/master/images/image_02.png</image>
      <caption>QC:Doom Edition</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum/master/images/image_03.png</image>
      <caption>Alphatius</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flathub/com.qzandronum.Q-Zandronum/master/images/image_04.png</image>
      <caption>Doomseeker browser</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
  <release version="1.4.20" date="2024-11-28">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.20</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Bots no longer fire their weapons in warmup state..</li>
          <li>You can no longer switch to spectator in singleplayer campaign unless sv_cheats is ON.</li>
          <li>Fixed user4 dash not working when jump button is pressed.</li>
          <li>Fixed midi soundfont default path and the fallback path.</li>
          <li>Fixed LumpOpen ACS function crash (thanks TDRR).Backported the latest SetPlayerClass ACS function code from Zandronum 3.2.</li>
          <li>Backported the Floor_Stop() and Ceiling_Stop() ACS functions from GZDoom.</li>
          <li>Fixed botepisode support and made it possible to create PvP campaigns with HUB levels. See below changes for details.</li>
          <li>Botepisode campaigns (PvP botmatch) are now displayed on top of PvE campaigns in episodes list.</li>
          <li>Leaving PvP gamemode campaign level now displays intermission.</li>
          <li>The ACS_Execute, ACS_ExecuteAlways and Teleport_NewMap functions now support string map names. Make sure to add a minus before the map name. For example: Teleport_NewMap(-"MAP02").</li>
          <li>Added campaignhub property to MAPINFO lump. It is supposed to be used in singleplayer botepisode campaigns to tell the deathmatch map where to go after the match has ended.</li>
          <li>Added botsSkillOffset property to CMPGNINF lump to offset bot skills up or down per each level individually.</li>
          <li>Added GAMEEVENT_MAP_COMPLETE event type (index 8) for EVENT scripts. This event is triggered after returning to HUB from a deathmatch match, and it's arguments provider the map name and info on whether the player won or not.</li>
          <li>Added support for setting custom cvars in CMPGNINF lump. The syntax is cvar cvarname = value.</li>
          <li>Added InCampaign() ACS function to tell whether the player is currently in a campaign.</li>
          <li>The map console command will no longer start a campaign if launching a campaign map. It has to be done via the "New Game" menu.</li>
          <li>FreeformMenu consinders singleplayer botmatch as singleplayer when using NotInSingleplayer flag.</li>
          <li>FreeformMenu only consinders PvP gamemodes as botmatch when using NotInBotplay flag.</li>
          <li>Fixed parsing player and bot team info in CMPGNINF lump.</li>
          <li>Fixed Respawn map scripts not running for players that respawned after map change.</li>
          <li>Fixed some cvars not setting correctly when set by CMPGNINF lump.</li>
          <li>Fixed botmatch campaign status not saving correctly in saved games.</li>
	</ul>
      </description>
  </release>	
  <release version="1.4.19" date="2024-09-26">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.19</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When turning off spectators vision in Team LMS, it only affects spectating dead players. True spectators can now see everyone despite the setting.</li>
          <li>Fixed ACS AnnouncerSound function local parameter playing all sounds in offline skirmish.</li>
          <li>FreeformMenu Command item text now dims when it's disabled.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
  </release>	  
  <release version="1.4.18" date="2024-09-17">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.18</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed players not updating their position in multiplayer.</li>
          <li>Fixed clearing dead player inventory before he drops important items like Terminator powerup.</li>
          <li>Fixed DEHACKED sprite changes not working.</li>
          <li>Added VelIntercept ACS function, which lets you aim actor at another actor based on his speed and your projectile speed.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.17" date="2024-09-05">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.17</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed bots not updating their position in multiplayer.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.16" date="2024-09-05">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.16</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Reduced jitter when spectating some players.</li>
          <li>Removed gl_sprite_blend option. The behavior is now as if the cvar was set to true. This is done to avoid some graphical bugs.</li>
          <li>Fixed particles having wrong offsets.</li>
          <li>Fixed reducing players speed when crouch button is pressed but crouching is disabled.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.15" date="2024-08-31">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.15</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Bouncing projectiles will now spawn decals on walls.</li>
          <li>Default bots will no longer crash the game when bot_disablenodes is true.</li>
          <li>Fixed black pixels instead of transparency on AMD videocards. This involved changing shaders in engine. As a result, old shader mods won't work properly anymore.</li>
          <li>Fixed quake movement characters playing run animation when stationary.</li>
          <li>Fixed toggle crouching not working properly in singleplayer.</li>
          <li>Fixed quake movement friction and acceleration on floors with increased friction.</li>
	  <li>Fixed attack z offset when crouching.</li>
	  <li>Negative Player.AttackZOffset makes attacks spawn relative to Player.ViewHeight instead of actor center. This way you can achieve consistent attack Z when crouching.</li>
	  <li>Added RGF_EXTRATRAIL flag for A_RailAttack. With this flag the function will spawn one extra trail actor at the end of the trail.</li>
	  <li>Added nofilter *texture* keyword to GLDEFS. This keyword disables texture filtering for given texture. This can be used on model textures too, just make sure to provide full texture path.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.14" date="2024-07-28">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.14</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added screen size controls binds to the menu.</li>
          <li>bot_disablenodes is no longer saved into engine ini file because having it ON crashes when using default engine bots.</li>
          <li>Partially fixed sprites splitting in two pieces and then improperly rotating when XY billboard is used.</li>
          <li>Fixed getting stuck on moving "Elevator_" specials.</li>
          <li>Fixed reloading strings after "restart" command.</li>
          <li>Added TagActive(int tag) ACS function that tells if a given tagged sector has some thinker attached to it.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.13" date="2024-05-20">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.13</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Made second jump only activate the moment the button is pressed, but never when button is already held.</li>
          <li>Added Freedoom 1.13 lumps for compatibility comparisons.</li>
          <li>Fixed view jittering when opening a console while zooming in or out.</li>
          <li>Fixed crash in CheckSolidFooting ACS function.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.11" date="2023-11-30">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.11.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.10" date="2023-11-11">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.10.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.9" date="2023-11-01">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.9.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.8" date="2023-10-21">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.8.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.6" date="2023-09-20">
      <description>
        <p>Update Q-Zandronum to 1.4.6.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.5" date="2023-09-03">
      <description>
        <p>First release of Q-Zandronum on Flathub.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <!--
	  Violence is tricky: You could argue that by 2019 standards, it's cartoonish.
	  In this regard I follow PEGI, who rates Doom 1993 with an age rating 16
	  for "bloody violence in an arcane setting"
    -->
    <content_attribute id="violence-realistic">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">moderate</content_attribute>
    <!-- Full multiplayer functionality -->
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
